A Guide to the Anna Clay Zimmerman Rutherford Papers, 1955-2008
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Anna Clay Zimmerman Rutherford Papers, 1955-2008
The Library of Virginia
51329
2.475 cubic feet (6 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Anna Rutherford, Tucson, Arizona.
Biographical Information
Anna Clay Zimmerman was born near Lewistown, Missouri on 3 March 1917. She is the daughter of Bertie Clay Zimmerman (1878-1926) and Anna Eliza Bowen (1885-1973). She attended Northeast Missouri State Teachers College in Kirksville, Missouri, and graduated from the University of Missouri in Columbia with a bachelor's degree in education (1952), and a master's degree in education (1955). She taught in various elementary and high schools in Missouri. On 20 November 1940, she married William Kenneth Rutherford (1907-1990). They published numerous genealogical books, including Genealogical History of the Halliburton Family (1959), Genealogical History of the Rutherford Family, (1969), Genealogical History of Our Ancestors (1970), and Genealogical History of the Gassaway Family (1981).
Scope and Content
Papers, 1955-2008, of Anna Clay Zimmerman Rutherford (b. 1917), and her husband William Kenneth Rutherford (1907-1990), of Lexington, Lafayette County, Missouri, containing their genealogical research for their two-volume work Genealogical History of Our Ancestors, published in 1970, and revised in 1977. There is information on the Bowen, Gardiner, Gassaway, Halliburton, Harper, Hayden, Peyton, Rutherford, Spalding, and Zimmerman families and allied lines that settled in Amherst, Essex, Richmond, and Stafford Counties, Virginia, and Kentucky, Maryland, Massachusetts, Missouri, North Carolina, Tennessee, and West Virginia. The collection includes clippings, correspondence, family group sheets, genealogical charts and pedigrees, and photostatic copies of deeds, estate accounts, inventories, and sales, land patents, marriage records, and wills.
Contents List
- Barnes, Comfort (d. 1760) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bass, Samuel (1600-1694) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Beaven, Charles (1640-1699) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Beedle, Henry (1645-1674) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Besson, Thomas (1616-1679) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Boarman, Mary (1660-1720) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Boarman, William (1630-1709) - Charles County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Boone, John (1655-1689) - Calvert County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Boone, Henrietta (1750-1827). (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Boone, James (d. 1753) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bowen. (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
- Bowen, Anna Eliza (1885-1973). (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bowen, John (b. 1805) - Clark County, MO. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Brooks, Grace (1662-1725) - Calvert County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Conrad. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Craycroft, Ann (1689-1765) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Craycroft, Ignatius (1666-1707) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Craycroft, John (1640-1690). (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Davis, Elizabeth (1816-1887) - Randolph County, MO. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Davis, Robert (1790-1860) - Montgomery County, TN. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Dyer, Patrick (d. 1720) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Edelen, Christopher (1682-1771) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Edelen, Philip (d. 1656) - County Buckingham, England. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Edelen, Richard (d. 1616) - Pinner Marsh, Parish of Harrow on the Hill. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Edelen, Richard (1635-1694) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Elledge, James (d. 1854) - Clark County, IL. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Elledge, Joseph (d. 1797) - Wilkes County, NC. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Ewen, Richard (1608-1663) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Ewen, Sophia (1650-1675) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Field, Edward. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Freeman, Edmund. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Freeman, John. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Gardiner, Eleanor. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Gardiner, Ignatius (1711-1777) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Gardiner, Luke (1622-1674) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Gardiner, Richard (1600-1649) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Gardiner, Richard (1645-1687) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Gassaway. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Gassaway, Benjamin - Frederick County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Gassaway, James. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Gassaway, Nicholas (1630-1691) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Gassaway, Nicholas (1696-1757) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Gassaway, Nicholas - Barren County, KY. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Gassaway, Samuel. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Genealogical Charts. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Gilkerson, John (1811-1896). (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Greene, James (d. 1734) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Greene, James (d. 1776) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Greene, Mary (d. 1716) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Greene, Robert (1646-1716). (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Greene, Gov. Thomas (1610-1651) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Hagan, Thomas (d. 1716) - Charles County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hall, Katherine (b. 1645) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Halliburton, Charles (d. 1797) - Caswell County, NC. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Halliburton, David (1727-1767) - Orange County, NC. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Halliburton, David (b. 1778) - Wake County, NC. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Halliburton, David (1753-1843) - Humphreys County, TN. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Halliburton, David Fletcher (1807-1883) - Gibson County, TN. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Halliburton, David Fletcher (1844-1921) - Gibson County, TN. (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Halliburton, John (1755-1843) - Person County, NC. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Halliburton, John (1774-1847) - Humphreys County, TN. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Halliburton, John Holloway (1803-1875) - Haywood County, TN. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Halliburton, Martin (1776-1860) - Dickson County, TN. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Halliburton, Reuben Pickett (1803-1882) - Sullivan County, MO. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Halliburton, Thomas White (1826-1894) - Randolph County, MO. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Harding, Robert. (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Harper. (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- Harper Descendants. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Harper, George Washington (1814-1882). (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Harper, Henry (1775-1830). (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Harper, Jacob (1726-1803). (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Harper, William Henry (1775-1830) - Lewis County, MO. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Harris, Richard. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Hatton, Margaret (b. 1595) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Hayden, Enoch (1760-1843) - Bourbon County, KY. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Hayden, Hannah (1805-1848). (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Hayden, John (1610-1684) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Hayden, Nehemiah (1647-1718) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Hayden, Samuel (b. 1683) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Hayden, William (1727-1823) - Hampshire County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Hiter. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Holmes, Obadiah (d. 1682). (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Holmes, Robert (d. 1604) - England. (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Holmes, Robert (d. 1640) - Reddich, England. (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Holmes, Samuel (1642-1679) - Gravesend, Long Island, NY. (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Humphreys, Evan. (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Huntsman, Benjamin (d. 1791) - Albemarle County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Huntsman, Josiah (d. 1805) - Lincoln County, KY. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Hutchinson, John (d. 1826) - Montgomery County, TN. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Jans, Anneke (1640-1663). (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Jansen, Roelof (1601-1636). (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Jenkins, Thomas (d. 1727) - Charles County,MD. (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Jett, Ann Delana (1842-1930) - Randolph County, MO. (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Jett, Asa H. (1815-1847) - Montgomery County, TN. (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Jett, Edward (1785-1845) - Montgomery County, TN. (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Johnson, James. (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Johnson, Matthew. (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Jones, Honoria (d. 1685) - Old Rappahannock County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Jones, Moses (d. 1706) - Charles County, MD. (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Judy, Margaret. (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Kierstede. (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Lawrence, Benjamin (d. 1685) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 3, Folder 38)
- McKinney. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- McKinney, Collin. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Merryman, John - Goochland County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Neale, Henry (1617-1688) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Offley, Hugh. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Page, Daniel (d. 1768) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Peyton, Ashcraft C. (1788-1846) - Macon County, MO. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Peyton, Catherine "Kitty" Holly (1855-1945) - Randolph County, MO. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Peyton, Daniel (1764-1825) - Floyd County, KY. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Peyton, John (1822-1894) - Shelby County, MO. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Peyton, Phillip (d. 1670) - Gloucester County, England. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Peyton, Phillip (1720-1790) - Amherst County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Peyton, Phillip (d. 1730) - Stafford County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Pray, Quinton (1597-1667) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Richardson. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Roach. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Roach, Ashcraft (d. 1815) - Amherst County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Roeloffson, Sara. (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Rogers, Martha Elizabeth (1828-1908) - Randolph County, MO. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Rutherford, James - Essex County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Rutherford, John (1689-1789) - Lincoln County, KY. (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Rutherford, Robert (1640-1730) - Essex County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Rutherford, Susannah (1775-1854) - Randolph County, MO. (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Rutherford, William Kenneth (b. 1907) - Lexington, MO. (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Sanford, Robert (d. 1700). (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Sebring. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- See, George (d. 1751) - Hardy County, VA. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- See, Mary Magdalene. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Shipley, Robert (d. 1763) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Spalding. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Spalding, Augustine (1569-1626) - Suffolk County, England. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Spalding, Basil (1710-1791) - Charles County, MD. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Spalding, James (1774-1852) - Nelson County, KY. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Spalding, James (d. 1800) - Prince George's County, MD. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Spalding, John (1480-1535) - Suffolk County, England. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Spalding, John (1590-1659) - Suffolk County, England. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Spalding, John (1658-1726) - Charles County, MD. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Spalding, Rebecca Ann (1826-1919) - Shelby County, MO. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Spalding, Thomas (1530-1573) - Suffolk County, England. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Spalding, Thomas (1630-1700) - St. Mary's County, MD. (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Spalding, Thomas James (1798-1828) - Nelson County, KY. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Stevens, Charles (d. 1703) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Stevens, Thomas - Talbot County, MD. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Stillwell, Nicholas (1612-1671) - Staten Island, NY. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Talbot. (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Talbot, Richard (1625-1666) - Anne Arundel County, MD. (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Turner, Rev. John. (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Vawter, Bartholomew (d. 1717) - Essex County, VA. (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Webb, Christopher (1630-1694) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Webb, Christopher (d. 1671) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Webb, Peter (1657-1718) - Suffolk County, MA. (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Weire, Honoria (b. 1630). (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Weir, John (1625-1671) - Old Rappahannock County, VA. (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Whaley, James (d. 1750) - Richmond County, VA. (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Whaley, James (d. 1784) - Loudoun County, VA. (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Woodford County, KY. (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Zimmerman. (Box 5, Folder 33-35)
- Zimmerman. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
- Zimmerman, Jacob. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Zimmerman, James Henry. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Zimmerman, James Henry (1849-1915) - Lewis County, MO. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Zimmerman, John. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Zimmerman, John Jr. (1801-1873) - Weakley County, TN. (Box 6, Folder 9)